Let's learn about stack operations.
There are some basic operations that allow us to perform different functions on a stack like Bush that
we have learned about it.
It is about adding an element to the top of the stack, removing.
An element from the top of the stack is known as pop on other operations is empty.
Check if the stack is empty is full, check if the stack is full and peak, get the value of the top
element without removing it.
We will see these operations in details in the following exercises.
And let's see and see how in the C language, how we can perform.
These so-called big method returns a copy of the element off the top of the stack without removing and
it's not like pop it speak.
Consider this stack.
We have the peak here and it's indicating number three.
So this is the peak of this stack.
It's just printing.
If we call the peak, it will print us for us a number three without popping it.
It's very important that you know it, without removing it, without popping it.
OK.
The other operations is checking if the stack is empty by using the method called is empty and return
to equal equal to minus one.
Okay, Boolean.
If the top equal equal to minus one, so the top is at the bottom, so there is no elements.
If it is no and it is not containing any elements inside the stack, then it will return true.
Otherwise, it is returning false.
OK.
Check if the stack is full, is full return dump equal capacity minus one it compare that top with a
capacity minus one.
The capacity minus one equal equal to the top level because but because it is minus one we have.
Start from index zero and the capacity took for a number higher than that, up by one.
So we decrease that capacity by one and we check the top.
And we compared it.
If it is true, then the stack is full.
Otherwise, it will return false.
How to chair at the present stack, it's very important to understand that we need to loop through all
the elements of the stack using a loop.
So for entire equal to zero I less than or equal to top I plus plus we increase it by plus plus in order
to go through all the elements of the stack system that allowed the print print the array at index.
I remember when dealing with it with arrays, you should use this.
Otherwise, if you are using a link, at least you need to make a loop.
But here we don't use the array we use.
That link is less than the size.
OK?
Now, stack implementation in see in the next video, we are going to see the stack implementation and
see with all that operations.
So this is.
The stack.
And we are going.
To see its functions, so this truck stack, it contains and items, the max and the end stop.
This is how we create a stack in.